http://www.calottery.com/privacy-policy

skip to main content
Home
Privacy Policy
PRIVACY POLICY
We protect your personal information.
The California State Lottery (www.calottery.com) is committed to protecting your privacy rights. It is the policy of the Lottery to limit the collection of your personal information and protect the personal information it collects and maintains.
The Lottery’s information management practices conform to the requirements of the Information Practices Act (California Civil Code section 1798 et seq.), the California Public Records Act (California Government Code section 6250 et seq.), California Government Code sections 11015.5 and 11019.9, California Business & Professions Code sections 22575-22579 and other laws pertaining to information privacy.
The Lottery adheres to the following principles in connection with the collection, use and sharing of your personal information:
The Lottery collects personal information from individuals only as allowed by law and with their explicit consent. The Lottery limits the collection of personal information to what is relevant and necessary to accomplish its lawful purpose, as defined in the California State Lottery Act. For example, the Lottery may need an individual’s home address, email address or telephone number in order to answer that person’s questions, process his or her claim form or provide some other requested assistance. The Lottery may also request demographic information such as ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites in order to personalize and improve its services. Website visitors who have registered on the Website may request to have their personal information discarded without reuse or distribution. To make such a request, contact the Lottery’s privacy coordinator at the following email address: privacy@calottery.com.
The Lottery does not collect home, business or email addresses or account information from people who simply browse the Lottery’s website, but it does automatically collect certain information from website visitors. The Lottery website consists of a primary domain and several sub-domains and is referred to collectively as “Website.” The Lottery only collects your personal information if you voluntarily provide it to us through email, registration forms or surveys. The Lottery does automatically collect some information from each visitor to its Website, including the domain name or Internet Protocol address that relates to the machine used to access the Website, the type of browser and operating system used, and the date and time when you visit the Website. The Lottery may also automatically collect information about your interaction with Lottery Website, mobile application and services. For example, it may use analytics tools on its Website to retrieve information from your browser, including the website you came from, the search engine(s) and the keywords you used to find the Lottery’s Website, the pages you view within the Lottery’s Website, your browser add-ons and your browser’s width and height. This automatically collected information is not subject to disclosure under the California Public Records Act.
This Website and Lottery mobile application (the “App”) use “cookies” and “anonymous identifiers” to help personalize your online experience and to collect usage statistics. Cookies store your site usage, preferences and user information, which will facilitate the future implementation of personalization and provide the Lottery with valuable information for site and application improvements. Anonymous identifiers are random strings of characters that are used for the same purposes as a cookie on platforms, including certain mobile devices, where cookie technology is not available. Cookies used by the Lottery are encrypted and cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.
The Lottery uses session cookies when you visit and search informational content on the Lottery’s Website. Session cookies do not contain user information, will not transmit any personal information to the Lottery and are deleted automatically when the browser window closes or within 24 hours, whichever occurs first.
The Lottery also uses persistent cookies, which you must manually delete. For example, the Lottery uses persistent cookies to collect username and language setting information.
To access certain Lottery Website and App services you will need to provide your email address and password (credentials). The Lottery will then assign and temporarily store your unique ID number and the time you signed in via an encrypted cookie on your computer or device. This cookie will allow you to move between services on the Website or App without having to sign in again on each page. When you sign out, these cookies are deleted from your computer or device.
The Lottery also uses cookies to improve your sign-in experience on the Website. For example, the Lottery may store your email address in a cookie that will remain on your computer after you sign out. This cookie allows the Lottery to pre-populate your email address the next time you sign in to the Website.
The Lottery also may permit third-party analytics providers, such as Google Analytics to use cookies and anonymous identifiers to collect and process certain non-personally identifiable information.  For example, Google Analytics may collect and process information such as how often users visit the Website or the App and, what pages they visited.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you will not be able to sign in or use other interactive features and services offered in the players’ area of the Lottery’s Website.
If you choose to accept cookies, you also have the ability to later delete cookies that you have accepted. For example, in Internet Explorer 10 you can delete cookies by selecting “Tools,” “Safety,” “Delete browsing history,” “Cookies” and “Delete.” Each browser may provide a different way to delete cookies. If you choose to delete cookies, any settings and preferences controlled by those cookies will be deleted and may need to be recreated when you next access the Website. The Lottery prohibits on its Website any third-party web beacons that collect or access your personal information.
In connection with the App, the Lottery may collect and store some or all of the information set forth below. This information enables you to use the App and receive information, products and services. It also enables the Lottery to respond to your inquiries or requests for products and services:
Device Information
The App may collect certain information about your device automatically when you download, connect to or use the App. Such information may include the type of mobile device you use and information about the way you use the App. The Lottery may receive such information and use it to operate and improve the App and to deliver services and content.
Ticket Information
To ensure the integrity of Lottery games and promotions, the Lottery may collect and store information about the tickets scanned by your device. Such information may be linked to a unique identifier that is associated with your device, the App software downloaded to your device or your 2nd Chance account.
Physical Location
Location information will not be collected without your consent. Location information enables the App to establish the approximate location of your mobile device. The Lottery may use and store this information, in combination with other location-based information (such as IP address), to provide requested location services (e.g., identification of nearby Retailers) and to deliver enhanced location-based services and other content. You may withdraw your consent to the collection of your location information at any time by disabling or changing the related functionality or setting as provided in your mobile device.
Telephone Number
The Lottery may also provide you with an opportunity to opt in to receive special offers on your wireless telephone by providing your wireless telephone number.
The Lottery’s Website collects anonymous cross-site data that is linked to the user’s device via a persistent identifier. The Lottery does not respond to “do not track” signals or other requests to terminate the collection of this data. Third parties may also use tracking cookies to collect anonymous cross-site data that is linked to a user’s device via a persistent identifier.
The Lottery may combine your information. In order to offer you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with the Lottery, the Lottery may combine information it collects through one Lottery service with information obtained through other Lottery and Lottery-affiliated services. The Lottery may also supplement the information it collects with information obtained from other companies. This will enable the Lottery, for example, to offer customized services based on location information determined by your computer IP address.
Whenever you are asked to provide personal information, the Lottery will tell you how that information will be used. The Lottery strives to inform individuals who provide personal information about the general uses that the Lottery will make of that information. The Lottery does this at the time of information collection.
The Lottery gives people who provide personal information an opportunity to review that information. The Lottery allows individuals who provide personal information to review that information and contest its accuracy or completeness. To make such a request, contact the Lottery’s privacy coordinator at the following email address: privacy@calottery.com.
The Lottery uses personal information only for purposes consistent with its Information Collection, Use and Access Notice.
The Lottery uses information security safeguards. The Lottery takes reasonable precautions to protect personal information it collects from loss, unauthorized access, illegal use and unauthorized disclosure. The Lottery uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption software to protect the security of individuals’ personal information during transmission of such information through the Lottery’s Website and the App. The Lottery takes reasonable security measures to protect your personal information in storage. The Lottery’s staff is trained on procedures for the management of personal information, including limitations on the release of information. Access to personal information is limited to those members of the Lottery’s staff and contractors whose work requires such access. The Lottery conducts periodic reviews to ensure that proper information management policies and procedures are understood and followed. In order to access some Lottery services, you will be asked to sign in using your credentials. Some services may require added security, and, in these cases, you may be asked to create an additional security key. The Lottery permanently records the IP address of the machine you use for registration and only stores the date and IP address of the last login thereafter. Finally, the Lottery will assign a unique ID number to your account, which will be used to identify your profile and associated information, such as login history and game play history.
In general, the Lottery encourages all individuals to use appropriate safeguards to secure their computers and the information on those computers.
The Lottery may access, preserve and disclose your account information and content, including messages, data, text and other types of works (collectively, “Content”) if required to do so by law or based on a good faith belief that such access, preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to:
Comply with legal process
Enforce the Terms of Service for the Lottery’s Website
Respond to claims that Content violates the rights of third parties
Respond to your requests for customer service, or
Protect the rights, property or personal safety of the Lottery, its users and the public.
The Lottery reserves the right, at its discretion, to change this privacy policy at any time. Please check this privacy policy periodically for changes. In the event that a change to this privacy policy materially modifies your rights or obligations, the Lottery will make reasonable efforts to notify you of such change. The Lottery may provide notice through a pop-up or banner within all Lottery-related websites and applications, by sending an email to any address you may have used to register for an account, or through other mechanisms.
The Lottery will provide additional information about this privacy policy if requested. If any individual has further questions about the Lottery’s privacy policy, they are encouraged to contact the Lottery’s Privacy Coordinator via email at  privacy@calottery.com or by mail addressed to: The California State Lottery - Attn: Privacy Coordinator, 700 North 10th Street, Sacramento, CA 95811.
Effective Date: August 5, 2019
